本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 苏三 栗子君 KK 许块块
校对： 君君不黑   后期： Pilar
前情提要
你怎么能偷自己主家的东西
You don't steal from your work family!
我非常抱歉 塞尔福里奇先生
I'm so sorry, Mr Selfridge.
我没看到边上有塞尔福里奇百货的标志
I don't see the Selfridge's livery on the side.
一直都是你给它装货吗
It's always you that loads it?
我都是听阿尔夫和萨姆的吩咐
I do what Alfie and Sam tell me.
你只是个售货员
You're a shop girl.
你的工作也丢了吧
Lost your job, have you?
你已经毁了一切 这下你还想要什么
You've done your damage. What more do you want?
我是塞尔福里奇夫人
I am Mrs.Selfridge.
你明知道我爱上了你
You knew I was falling in love with you.
是要报复爱伦・乐芙那件事吗 是吗
Was it revenge for Ellen Love, was that it?
你跟塞尔福里奇百货的合同终止了
Your contract with Selfridge's is over.
我怎么没见到你太太
I don't see your wife anywhere!
我太太不需要你关心 再见 爱伦
My wife is not your concern. Goodbye, Ellen.
翻译
苏三
栗子君
翻译
KK
许块块
校对
君君不黑
后期
Pilar
塞尔福里奇先生
第一季第五集
这项目看来花费不菲啊 塞尔福里奇先生
This seems a rather expensive enterprise, Mr Selfridge.
它会带来更多的利润
It will more than pay for itself.
那要怎么把它弄进橱窗里?
How will we get it in the window?
这你不用担心 恩里是老手了
Don't worry about that. Henri's an old hand.
我们会先拆开它 然后再拼起来
We'll dismantle it and then put it together.
天啊
My God!
我们以前就在马歇尔・费兹百货轻而易举地做到
It worked like a dream for us at Marshall Field.
而在那时
But back then,
整个芝加哥只有一千五百人有驾照
there were only 1,500 registered drivers in the whole of Chicago.
而如今的伦敦 则超过三万六千人有驾照
In London today, there are over 36,000.
他们将会经过 他们将会看到
They'll come, they'll see,
他们将会走进来 他们将会买下这个车
they'll walk inside and they'll buy the products.
她很美对吧
Isn't she a beauty?
保险公司可不办理开这个车的保险啊
This automobile is not insured for anyone to drive.
即使是你 塞尔福里奇先生
Not even you, Mr Selfridge.
你怎么想
What do you think?
- 太棒了! - 橱窗要怎么摆
- Magnificent! - How is the window shaping up?
"驶向新时代"
"Motoring for the Modern Age!"
嗯 我真想念艾格尼思・陶勒小姐的敏锐眼光
Well, I miss Agnes Towler's keen eye.
那就让她和你一起工作
So get her to work with you.
我不能 她走了
I can't. She's gone.
走了?
Gone?
什么 你不知道吗
What? Didn't you know?
他父亲闹事之后 她就离职了
After that business with her father, she has left.
算了 至少乔治还有工作
Well, at least George is still in work.
要是没了他那份薪水 我真不知道会怎样
Without his wages, I don't know where we'd be.
你会关照他的 对吧
You'll look out for him, won't you?
当然会
Course I will.
我爸又回来了
My dad's come back.
我还以为你已经换锁了
I thought you'd changed the locks?
他昨晚喝多了 在楼道里晕过去了
He turned up last night, drunk, passed out on the stairs.
房东夫人说如果不解决好他的事
My landlady told me if I didn't get him out of the way,
那我们都得离开
that we'd all be out.
我们一定要想个办法
We'll have to work out something.
他不能永远呆在这里 我一直在想
He can't stay here forever. I've been thinking...
或许你丢了工作也不是件坏事
maybe it's not so bad you left your job.
为什么
What?
对你我来说
Well, for you and me.
我们现在可以约会了
We can go out together now.
我们这周末一起去布莱顿吧
How about we go down to Brighton this weekend?
布莱顿?我们去那里做什么?
Brighton? What would we do there?
月光下牵着手 在码头沙滩上漫步
Walk on the beach, go down the pier, hold hands in the moonlight.
我知道你想让我高兴起来 但我真的没心情
I know you're trying to cheer me up, but I'm not in the mood.
我是在追求你
I'm asking if I can court you.
这才是我要做的事情
That's what I'm doing
哦 我懂了
Oh, I see.
你从来没想过吗
Hadn't it crossed your mind at all?
没怎么想过
Not really.
好吧 也许想过一点...
Well, maybe a bit...
一点?好吧 我想是个好开始
A bit? Well, I suppose that's a start.
我喜欢你 维克托 你知道的
I like you, Victor, you know I do.
但我麻烦事太多 不值得你这样
But I'm more trouble than I'm worth.
考虑到乔治和我爸 还有我失去工作的事
What with George and my dad, and me without a job.
你不会愿意追求我的
You don't want to court me.
我愿意 胜过一切
I do. More than anything.
那你就是我女朋友了?
Are you my girl then?
我想我只好是了
I think I must be.
陶勒小姐在吗 一向是陶勒小姐招呼我的
Miss Towler available? I always deal with Miss Towler!
我不能想象把这个戴在头上
I can't imagine wearing that over my face.
是要挡开嘴边的苍蝇吧
Keeps the flies out of your mouth, I suppose.
卡莱尔夫人来了 马德尔小姐
Lady Carlyle's here, Miss Mardle.
她想要看我们所有的驾驶手套
She wants to see all the motoring gloves that we've got.
那就给她看啊
Well, show them to her!
她说要陶勒小姐去
She's asking for Miss Towler.
告诉她陶勒小姐离职了 但你能帮她
Tell her Miss Towler has left, but you can help her.
挺背伸肩 注意措词
Shoulders back, good diction.
这是我们这里最柔软的皮手套 卡莱尔夫人
Those are the most supple leather we have, Lady Carlyle.
手掌处的磨面能让驾驶者更好抓稳方向盘
The abrasions on the palm allow the driver to grip the steering wheel.
该如何向顾客解释艾格的事呢 马德尔小姐
What are we to say to customers about Agnes, Miss Mardle?
你们只需客气有礼地协助客人完成购物
You'll be courteous and assist them with whatever they are looking for.
继续工作吧 多芮斯
Now get on with your work, Doris.
一眼看上去就有驾驶感觉的东西
It must say 'Motoring', at a glance.
你有什么推荐
What do you have?
这是多萝西・莱维款法兰绒上衣
This is the Dorothy Levitt blazer,
多萝西・莱维
英国最早的女赛车手 被誉为"世界上最快的女子"
灵感来自于这位伟大赛车手本身
inspired by the great motorist herself.
有没有女人在各种场合都可以穿戴的
A woman could wear this anywhere,
包括散步 骑车甚至是参加游园会?
walking, bicycling, even to a garden party. No?
我刚好有件大衣
I have just the coat.
是新来的
It's new in.
最近正好流行皮大衣
It also comes in leather.
穿皮大衣的女士 这个够吸引吗 勒卡雷先生
A lady in leather...does that appeal, Mr Leclair?
非常吸引 勒维利厄斯小姐
Very much, Miss Ravillious.
皮大衣不错 谢谢你
Leather is good, thank you.
你和塞尔福里奇夫人有预约过吗
Do you have an appointment to see Mrs Selfridge?
她会见我的 跟她说是我就行
She'll see me. Just tell her I'm here.
露思!
Rose!
- 塞尔福里奇夫人 - 没事的 弗朗瑟
- Mrs Selfridge. - It's alright, Fraser.
抱歉 坦普尔先生 我都忘了你要过来
Apologies, Mr Temple. I'd forgotten that I was expecting you.
我看到你把画带来了 请进吧
I see you've brought the painting. Please, come in.
你来这里做什么
What are you doing here?
听我说 我 我是来为那天的事道歉的
Look, I, erm... I came to apologise for the other day.
我对你太无礼而且
I was rude to you and...
嗯 我一直感觉很糟糕
Well, I've been feeling awful about it.
我也很抱歉 我不该对你隐瞒身份
I'm sorry too. I shouldn't have lied about who I was.
没事
No.
我们还是朋友?
Friends?
看情况吧
It depends.
看什么情况
On what?
看这个 拜托 我想看死了
On this! Come on, I'm dying to see it!
- 可以吗 - 当然 请
- Can I? - Yes. Please...
真不相信你居然完成了
I can't believe you've finished it!
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
与你之前所画的完全不一样
It's nothing like you've done before.
我说过 是你赋予了我灵感
I told you, you inspire me.
画得好 真的很好
It's good. It's really good.
谢谢你
Thank you.
哈里会喜欢它的
Harry will like it.
我不想让他拥有它
I don't want him to have it.
你还不明白吗
Don't you see?
如今你把画带进这个屋子 我必须要给他的
Now you've brought it into the house, I have to give it to him.
我有为人妻的责任 而我一直假装没有
I have responsibilities and I've been pretending I haven't -
你丈夫忽视你
Your husband neglects you.
不 我爱他 而且...
No, I love him and...
他也以他的方式爱着我
he loves me too, in his own way.
不像我这么爱你
Not like I could.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是你妈妈的一个朋友
I'm a friend of your mother's.
这是坦普尔先生...他一直为我画像
This is Mr Temple, and... he's been painting my picture.
我要把它当作礼物送给你爸爸
I'm gonna give it to Pa as a present.
你在画画!
You're painting!
没错 我以前经常画画 在你出生之前
Yes, I used to paint, before you came along.
好了 去你奶奶那里吧
Now, run along to Grandma.
我正要送坦普尔先生离开
I'm just gonna see Mr Temple out.
还有 碧翠丝亲爱的
Oh, and Beatrice darling...
别跟任何人说这事
don't tell anyone about this.
这是个惊喜
It's a surprise.
噢 天啊
Oh no!
她会说出去吗
Will she say anything?
我不知道 你得走了
I don't know. You have to go.
你必须走了!
You have to go!
我不能走
I can't.
你本质根本不是一个旧式女人
You're not a conventional person at heart.
不要扼杀你的真我 这可能是你的最后机会
Don't stifle your true self. This may be your last chance.
不行
No...
No.
你还会再见到我的
You'll see me again.
记住这话
You can depend on that.
它能开多快
How fast does it go?
每小时四五十英里
Forty, fifty miles an hour.
当你在车轮之上的时候
When you're behind the wheel of one of these,
将体会到那种速度之快 一切都无法超越你
you feel like you're going so fast, that nothing can touch you.
我也想开汽车
I wanna drive one.
总有一天会的
You will one day.
我们被发现了 戈顿!
We've been spotted, Gordon!
不要怕 准备好...
Be brave, prepare for....
过来这里 你
Come here, you!
我有一个不能告诉你的秘密
I've got a secret that I can't tell you.
真的吗 那我就挠你痒痒 不信你不说 说吧
You do? Well, I'm gonna tickle it out of you! Come on!
什么秘密
What is it?
现在几点 很晚了吗
What time is it? Is it late?
哈里 你不该现在打开的
Harry, you shouldn't have opened it.
这是给你的礼物
It was a present for you.
我还不知道你这么想念作画
I didn't realise that you missed painting.
是啊 我之前也没意识到
Yeah, I don't think I realised it either.
是谁画的
Who's the artist?
一个叫罗德里克・坦普尔的人
He's called Roderick Temple.
他捕捉到了你的神韵 你在哪里见到他的
He caught you well. Where did you meet him?
在国家美术馆
At the National Gallery.
那他在哪里画你的
And where did he paint you?
在他的画室里
In his studio.
哈里 他只是个男孩
Harry, he's just a boy.
如果我认为让他画我有任何不妥的话
If I'd considered it at all inappropriate to be painted by him,
我是根本不会过去的
I wouldn't have gone ahead with it!
我是想着你可以挂它在你办公室里
I thought you could hang it in your office,
就在你办公桌对面的墙上
on the wall opposite your desk.
但如果你不喜欢它
But if you don't like it...
我只是希望能早点知道 仅此而已
I just wish I'd known, that's all.
如果你知道了 那就不是惊喜了 对吧
If you had, it wouldn't have been a surprise, would it?
你知道我珍惜你胜过一切
You know I value you, more than anything.
是的 哈里 我知道
Yes Harry, I know that.
你这么早要去哪里
Where are you off to so early?
有件事情我必须去做
There's something I need to do.
我到了
I got it.
在这里等我一下 谢谢你
Wait right here for me, thank you.
给我钱 给我钱
Give me money! Give me money!
你是头儿对吧
Oh, is that the biggest one?
好了 钱不是一直就在你这里嘛
There we go. You had the money the whole time, right there!
哈哈 我要投降了
Ha ha! I'm outnumbered!
当然 你要再给自己找份工作
Of course, you'll have to get yourself another job.
我是说 我们三个不能只靠乔治那点薪水
I mean, we can't all three of us live off George's wages.
你是谁
Who are you?
前门开着 我来找艾格尼思・陶勒
The front door was open. I'm looking for Agnes Towler.
我们不允许男访客进来
We don't accept gentlemen callers.
在那里等下
Wait in there.
听着 我有个朋友 他在波普勒有一间酒吧
Here, I've got a mate, and he owns this pub in Poplar,
他在找酒吧女侍应
and he's looking for a bar maid.
酒吧女侍应?
A bar maid?
那又怎么了 你能做这个就算幸运了
What's wrong with that? You're lucky to get the offer.
有人来找你 我让他在前面客厅等着
Swell downstairs for you.I put him in the front parlour.
塞尔福里奇先生
Mr Selfridge!
你在这...你在这里做什么
What are... What are you doing here?
我也想问你这个问题
I could say the same for you.
为什么你不在商场里
Why aren't you at the store?
我离职了
I left.
我不接受 我是来带你回去的
I won't accept it. I'm here to take you back.
你很有潜质
You show great potential.
你让我回想起刚起步的自己
You remind me of myself when I started out.
紧抓每一个机会 对学习充满热情渴望
Grasping for every chance, keen as mustard to learn.
你很喜欢 对吧
You love it, don't you?
这种服务顾客 销售商品 运筹帷幄的感觉
The customers, the selling, the feel of the merchandise under your hands.
我喜欢它 胜于一切
I love it more than anything.
所以我不想失去你
That's why I don't wanna lose you.
回来吧 谁会在乎你父亲做过的事?
Come back. Who cares what happened with your father?
只要你不在乎 别人就不会在乎
If you don't, no one else will.
但是塞尔福里奇先生 你也不在乎吗
But Mr Selfridge, don't you?
你又不是你父亲
You're not him.
所有的 呃
All the, erm...
麻烦在于 我似乎没办法摆脱他
I can't seem to find my way out of it, that's the trouble.
每次我设法安排好自己和乔治离开他
Every time I try to set myself and George up without him,
他都会找到我们
he finds us.
谢谢你
Thank you.
他现在在家吗?
Is he in the house now?
让我和他谈谈
Let me go talk to him.
你他妈谁啊?
Who the bloody hell are you?
哈里・戈顿・塞尔福里奇
Harry Gordon Selfridge.
我是来给你提几个条件的
I have certain conditions to put before you.
什么条件?
What conditions?
马上离开伦敦
Leave London immediately.
随便什么地方 只要离这里足够远
Live anywhere you like as long as it's a good distance from here.
你他妈以为自己是谁啊?
Who the hell do you think you are?
你随便到这里拜访
You come round here,
还以为能随便吩咐我做事?
and you think that you can tell me what to do?
这些足够付你的车马费
This should pay for your travel,
让你在找到工作之前饱腹了
keep food in your stomach while you look for work.
哦 我懂了
Oh, I get it.
你喜欢上我女儿艾格
You have taken a bit of a shine to my Aggie.
给我说说 她给你提供服务了吗
Tell me, has she offered her services to you?
- 啊! - 给我听好!
- Argh! - Understand me!
即使你继续酗酒下去 最终流落街头
If you drink your way through this and end up on the street,
你也不能回来伦敦骚扰你女儿
you will not return to London to bother your daughter!
你不能联系她
You will not contact her,
也不能到我商场来找她
you will not come to my store and seek her out.
我不会让你毁了她的生活的
I will not let you ruin her life!
好了 停!停!停!停!
All right, stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
停下!停下!求你了!停下!
Stop! Stop! Please! Stop!
求你了
Please!
我们达成共识了吧
Do we have an agreement?
你好 儿子
Hello, son.
你爸才不是战争英雄 他也还没死呢
'Your pa ain't no war hero. He ain't dead either!'
我妈说他还活着 住在加州费利蒙市
'My ma says he's alive and living in Freemont...'
爸爸?
Pa?
那位女士是谁 爸爸?
Who is that lady, Pa?
为什么你不回家和妈妈与我一起住
Why aren't you at home with Ma and me?
你妈妈那套高尚的胡话逼我这样的
Your ma's high-toned bullshit did it for me,
所以我永远不会回家
that's why I never came home.
但你我血肉相连 不论你喜欢与否
But I'm your blood and you're mine, whether you like it or not...
塞尔福里奇先生?塞尔福里奇先生?
Mr Selfridge? Mr Selfridge?
塞尔福里奇先生?
Mr Selfridge?
一切都还好吧
Is everything all right?
你今晚下班回家时 他就会已经离开
He'll be gone by the time you get back from work this evening.
什么意思
What do you mean?
就是离开的意思
Just what I say - gone.
这种情况下 最好就是一刀两断
In this type of situations, it's best to make a clean break.
没有矫情的告别 懂了吗
No fond farewells. You understand?
拿上你的大衣和帽子 我载你去店里
Grab your coat and hat. I'll give you a ride into the store.
好了 你喜欢这趟车程吗
Well, did you enjoy the ride?
感觉像飞一样
It felt like flying!
说不准 或许真有一日 你也会飞呢
Who knows? One day, you may do that as well.
谢谢你 塞尔福里奇先生
Thank you, Mr Selfridge.
好了 你记住 无需道歉 无需解释
Now, you remember. Don't apologise, don't explain.
我总是用这一招应付得很好
As a tactic, it's always worked well for me.
- 谢谢你 - 这没什么
- Thank you. - That's all right.
看!
Look!
她回来做什么
What's she doing back?
我能帮你什么吗 陶勒小姐?
Can I help you, Miss Towler?
我回来了 马德尔小姐
I've come back, Miss Mardle.
嗯 恐怕不可能吧 亲爱的
Well, I'm afraid that's not possible, my dear.
这是个误会 我没递交辞呈
It was a mistake. I didn't hand in my notice.
只要查一下
If you check,
就会发现我还是塞尔福里奇百货的员工
I'm still employed by Selfridge's,
由塞尔福里奇先生聘用
by Mr Selfridge.
好吧 当然我得向格罗夫先生确认一下
Right, well, I will have to confirm that with Mr Grove of course.
但同时 我们可以先让你上班了
But in the meantime, we can put you to use.
你可以拆开新到的货
You can unpack the new stock.
我们正着手做汽车用品的推广
We are embarking on a motor driving promotion
还有这些膝毯是刚回来的
and those lap robes have just come in.
好的 马德尔小姐
Very good, Miss Mardle.
你不能这样子就回来了
You can't just swan back in.
看来我已经这样做了
Looks like I just have.
- 陶勒小姐 - 你好
- Miss Towler! - Hello.
你回来了
You've returned to us.
这真太好了
That is wonderful.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
乔治小伙
George lad.
把这个给我们然后过来
Give us an 'and over here.
我正要搬完
I'll just finish this.
马上的!
Now!
谢谢你
Thank you.
我是爱伦・乐芙 来见塞尔福里奇太太的
Miss Ellen Love, to see Mrs Selfridge.
乐芙小姐 真是惊喜
Miss Love, what a pleasant surprise.
我恐怕这并不是单纯的社交性拜访
I'm afraid this isn't a social visit,
塞尔福里奇夫人
Mrs Selfridge.
哦?真是遗憾
Oh? What a pity.
呃 请问你要点咖啡吗
Er, please, can I offer you some coffee?
我是来告诉你 你的丈夫对你并不忠诚
I'm here to tell you that your husband has not been faithful to you.
他一直与我在谈婚外情
He's having an affair with me.
嗯 我想我还是要点咖啡好了
Well, I think I'll have some, anyhow.
这就是你所要说的?
Is that all you can say?
好吧 这消息对我来说也不是意外了
Well, this news isn't a surprise to me.
我第一次看到你们在一起时 我就知道了
I knew from the moment I first saw you two together.
但是你来告诉我的话
But the fact that you are here, telling me about it...
倒是很有趣
Well, that is of interest.
这就意味着 你们的关系基本上已经结束了
It suggests that it's almost certainly over.
你真冷酷无情
You're so cold.
难怪哈里到别处寻找激情
No wonder Harry looks for his passions elsewhere.
你很想要拥有他 对吧
You've got him bad, haven't you?
他爱我
He loves me.
呃 这我倒是不相信
Mm, I very much doubt that.
哈里之前就出轨过不少次
Harry has had many similar liaisons.
你不过是漫长的舞女队伍中
You are the latest
新来的那一个
in a long line of chorus girls.
我才不是一个舞女
I'm not a chorus girl!
那我得承认 或许是我丈夫让你误会了吧
That, I admit, could be a mistake on my husband's part.
如果没有别的事的话
Unless there is anything else...
今天是我的家务整理日
..today is my housekeeping day.
噢 乐芙小姐正要离开 弗朗瑟
Oh, Miss Love was just leaving, Fraser.
请给我一杯咖啡吧
And I'll have a coffee please.
告诉他我来过
Tell him I came.
还有 我不会这么轻易被甩的
And I will not be got rid of that easily.
老大在吗
Is the chief in?
他心情怎样了
How's his mood?
我心情好得很 格罗夫先生
My mood is just fine, Mr Grove.
怎么了 出什么问题了
Why? What's the problem?
装卸区的偷窃?
Thieving in the loading bay?
这商场在搞什么鬼
What the hell is wrong with this store?
把他们当场抓住 然后狠狠地扔出去
Catch them red-handed and throw them out on their ear.
你是怎么发现的
How did you discover this?
棕榈宫饭店里一位叫维克托 克里诺的侍应
Victor Colleano, a waiter in the Palm Court,
他来找我说出他的怀疑
came to me, voiced his suspicions.
还好 至少还是有忠诚的人的
Well, at least there's some loyalty.
塞尔福里奇先生 我会处理这件事的
I'll deal with it, Mr Selfridge.
还有 格罗夫先生
Oh, and Mr Grove...
陶勒小姐回来工作了
Miss Towler is back on the pay roll.
但她不是辞职了吗
But she left.
如果没有的话 我也已经解雇她了
If she hadn't, I'd have dismissed her.
这里面有点误会
That would have been a mistake.
可她父亲当众出丑了
Her father behaved disgracefully.
她父亲不会影响到她 起码在我商场里不会
The parent is not the child. Not in my store anyway.
那我就是要允许本婷小姐回来
So am I to allow Miss Bunting to return,
而且对装卸区的偷窃也眼开眼闭?
and turn a blind eye to these loading bay workers?
那可不一样 他们偷了我们的东西
That is different. They stole from us.
员工们会不理解 为什么她能回来工作
The staff will not understand why she has been allowed to return.
放心 稍后我会解释的
Well, then I will explain it.
今晚召开员工大会
Call a staff meeting this evening.
通知所有部门的主管
Let the heads of each department know.
乔治把那些都搬上去
George, load that stuff an' all.
乔治 我得和你谈谈 马上的
George, I need to talk to you, urgent!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
这是个阴谋 你还不懂吗
It's a fiddle. Don't you get it?
见鬼!
Bloody hell!
那是哈里・塞尔弗里奇先生的财产
That is the property of Mr Harry Selfridge!
你们被解雇了 滚出去
Out on your ear! Get out!
我还一直给那货车装货
I've been loading that van!
什么都不要说 要是有人问起 你也别多嘴
Don't say anything. If anyone asks, keep your mouth shut.
我还一直当阿尔夫是朋友
And I thought Alf was my friend.
我才是你的朋友 好吧
I'll be your friend, alright?
- 谢了 维克托 - 但你要醒目点
- Thanks, Victor. - But you need to wise up.
你姐姐丢了工作 正沮丧呢
Your sister's out of a job, feeling cut up.
- 她有工作了 - 她找到工作了?
- She's ain't out of a job no more! - She found something?
她不是回来这里吗 她回来塞尔福里奇百货了
She's back here, isn't she? She's back at Selfridges.
我想要摆置一家人坐在里面
I want to put a whole family in it.
父亲 母亲 孩子们
Father, mother, children.
汽车要倾斜一点 就好象在飞一样
And the motor will be at an angle, so it is almost flying.
要知道 这对孩子来说就跟童话一样
You know for the children, it has to be like a fairy tale.
他们要开往公园 在空中挥舞着草帽
They are going to the park, straw hats, which they wave in the air.
丝巾在他们身后飘扬
Scarves, flowing out behind them.
男孩穿着水手服
A sailor suit for the boy.
女孩穿着白色背心裙
A little white pinafore for the girl.
这一定会很美
It's going to be beautiful!
我很高兴你能回来
I'm glad you're back.
你一定很兴奋吧
This could be an exciting time for you.
塞尔福里奇先生居然亲自把你带回来
Mr Selfridge has brought you back personally.
塞尔福里奇先生真是世上最好的人
Mr Selfridge is THE best man in the world!
是吗
He is?
他不仅让我回来工作
He hasn't just given me my job back.
他还 呃 他还把我爸爸劝离伦敦了
He's, erm... He's persuaded my dad to leave town.
我难以表达我有多高兴
I can't tell you how good that feels.
要知道 世界正对你敞开
You know, the world is opening up to you.
如果你接触到它 你会有更多可学的
There is so much to learn, if you reach out and take it.
看来 乐芙小姐的时代要终结了
So, Miss Love's day is over.
问题是 谁将会取代她呢
The question is - who will take her place?
他推翻我所做的每个决定
He overrides every decision I make.
我可是他的总务主管 紧急关头
I'm his Chief of Staff! In an emergency,
我可能会接手管理这个商场 可他却不重视我
I would take over running the store. But he doesn't value me.
罗杰 我肯定他不是不重视的
Roger, I'm sure that's just not true.
也许该提出辞职的人是我
Perhaps it is I who should tender my resignation.
不 你不能这样
No, you mustn't!
你是唯一理解我的人
You're the only one who really understands me.
马德尔小姐
Miss Mardle.
劳斯利女士
Lady Loxley.
今天有什么我能帮到您的吗
How can I help you today?
我想要看一下足套 开车用的
I'd like to see your collection of foot muffs, for motoring.
很好 谢谢你
Very good! Thank you!
六点整 楼下开员工大会
Staff meeting, 6 o'clock, downstairs.
塞尔福里奇先生
Mr Selfridge.
梅女士 见到您真高兴
Lady Mae, what a pleasure!
托尼・特拉夫
Tony Travers.
你家人还好吧 可爱的露思琳还好吧
How's the family? How's the charming Rosalie?
噢 她很好 谢谢关心
Oh, she's well, thank you.
很好 那亲爱的塞尔福里奇老夫人呢
Good. And dear Mrs Selfridge?
噢 她也很好
Oh, she's well too.
塞尔福里奇 我还不知道你夫人是风雅的人呢
I didn't know you wife was the artistic sort, Selfridge.
前几天 我在切尔西艺术俱乐部见到她
I saw her at the Chelsea Arts Club the other day.
她和罗德里克・坦普尔聊得真挺开心的
She was having a pretty good time with Roddy Temple.
他是在给露思画肖像画呢
He's been painting a portrait of Rose.
噢 真不错啊
Oh, how wonderful.
我还没机会谢谢你
I didn't get a chance to thank you -
他是那种不羁的艺术家
He's a Bohemian sort of chap,
而且那个艺术俱乐部真有风情
and The Arts Club is a pretty racy place.
真没想到塞尔福里奇夫人会去那里
I wasn't expecting to see Mrs Selfridge there.
托尼 你想法太过时了
Tony, you are so behind the times.
自从拉特兰公爵夫人频繁出入那里之后
Since the Duchess of Rutland started to frequent it,
每个人都想被看到出现在那里
everyone who's anyone wants to be seen there.
塞尔福里奇夫人去那里真是明智之举
How clever of Mrs Selfridge to gain entrance.
好了 允许我先失陪
And now, if you'll excuse me.
那真是幼稚
That was childish.
嗯 我很乐在其中
Well, I enjoyed myself.
如果你再准备这样做的话 就先告诉我
If you're going to do something like that, tell me first.
就不允许我有自己想法吗
Aren't I even allowed to think for myself?
不 重点完全不在于你
No! That's not the point of you at all.
事实上 我也不清楚重点是什么了
In fact I'm no longer sure what the point is.
那好了 请允许我失陪了
Well then, if you'll excuse me.
你真是一个多才多艺的男人
You're a man of many talents.
你肯定不甘心永远呆在这里 你有什么抱负吗
You can't want to work here forever. Do you have ambitions?
我想要在苏活区开一家自己的餐厅
I want to open my own restaurant in Soho.
我有关系 也有些权力
I have friends and some influence.
还有个厨师患上了百日咳
I also have a chef with whooping cough.
今晚来为我做饭吧
Come and cook for me this evening.
或许我们能进一步讨论此事呢
We could perhaps discuss this matter further?
塞尔福里奇夫人的肖像画真有意思
What an interesting painting of Mrs Selfridge.
布伦金索普小姐
Miss Blenkinsop!
给我妻子送四十朵白玫瑰
I'd like 40 white roses sent round to my wife.
不 五十朵好了
No, make it 50.
我还以为我们昨天都商量好了
I thought we decided yesterday,
你不在这里工作是件好事 对我们来说
it was a good thing you don't work here - for us.
塞尔福里奇先生亲自过来
Mr Selfridge came over himself.
他邀请我回来工作 还用汽车载了我一程
He asked me back, gave me a ride in his motor!
维克托 我从未感到如此自豪过
Victor, I've never felt so proud!
我想还是可以偷偷约会的
I suppose we can court anyway, on the quiet.
来吧 去拿大衣 我们走吧
Come on, get your coat. Let's get out of here.
塞尔福里奇先生要讲话呢
Oh, Mr Selfridge is giving a talk.
他不会发现我们的
He won't miss us.
我一定要留在这里
I have to stay.
那之后呢 我带你去吃晚餐吧
After, then. How about I take you out for a meal?
我叔叔在克勒肯维尔有家餐厅
My uncle's got this place in Clerkenwell.
不 今晚不行
I can't, not tonight.
我答应了勒卡雷先生帮他准备明天的橱窗
I said to Mr Leclair that I'd help with the window for tomorrow.
那个人打个响指 你就跑着过去
That man snaps his fingers, you come running.
我想要跟你一起
I want to be with you.
我也想啊 可我答应勒卡雷先生了
I want that too. But I promised Mr Leclair.
如果我让他失望
If I let him down,
就等于让塞尔福里奇先生失望
it'd be as if I was letting Mr Selfridge down.
那要是让我失望呢
What about letting me down?
你为求目的 什么都可以说
You'll say anything to get your way.
要知道 我很厌倦听人摆布
You know, I'm fed up of being told what to do.
我不是要摆布你
I'm not telling you what to do.
觐见国王必须穿白色 梅女士说的
You have to wear white to be presented, Lady Mae says.
所有年轻女孩都这样穿
All the young girls do.
这件很漂亮 你觉得呢
This one's pretty, don't you think?
我觉得这裙裾不怎么好
I'm not sure about the train.
一定要有裙裾的
You must have a train!
而且我要开始习惯了 到时真正觐见时
And I have to get used to them. When I eventually get presented,
从肩膀算起 裙裾长度要不少于三码
the train has to be no less than three yards in length from the shoulders.
听起来挺繁琐做作的
It sounds rather ornate.
这是传统嘛
It's tradition.
给您的 塞尔福里奇夫人
For you, Mrs Selfridge.
噢
Oh!
白玫瑰 太美了
White roses, they are so beautiful!
哈里送的?
From Harry?
谢谢你 弗朗瑟 请先放在水里吧
Thank you, Fraser. Will you put them in water?
我待会再摆好
I'll arrange them later.
它们真美丽
How lovely they are!
我真希望找到像爸爸这样的丈夫
I hope I find a husband like Pa.
我想要跟大家说点事
I wanted to talk to you about something
对我来说 非常重要的事
that's very important to me.
诚实
Honesty.
我们这个商场崇尚的是正直诚信
We believe in upright behaviour in this store.
每位顾客都可以信赖于
Every customer can trust
他们所买的东西物有所值
they are getting exactly what they're paying for.
他们两个真般配 对吧
They make a lovely couple, don't they?
我以此为傲
I am proud of that!
我希望你们也能以此为傲
I hope you are proud too.
但即使这里 也有违规行为
But even here, standards can slip.
你偷商场的东西 就等于偷自己的东西
You steal from this store, you steal from yourselves.
你看 你们都应该知道我是役童起家的
Now, you all probably know I started off as an errand boy.
在我十岁的时候 我一周挣一美元五十分
I was ten years old, I earned a dollar fifty a week.
他们提升去我管理货仓的那天
The day they promoted me to stock boy,
我激动得差点哭了
I damn near cried.
而在他们交给我钥匙
And then when they gave me the key
让我早上到商场里开门的时候
to open up the store in the morning...
那天 我毕生难忘
that's the day that I... I won't forget.
经理信任我
The manager trusted me.
没有信任 你将一事无成
Without trust, you can't run anything.
我想 我要说的是
I guess what I'm trying to say is,
我不能容忍欺骗的行为
I won't tolerate dishonesty.
但如果你需要帮助 随时来找我
But I'm here for you, if you need my help.
最近 一名员工因为她家人的愚蠢行为
Recently, a member of our staff thought she had to leave her position
以为自己必须离职
because a member of her family behaved foolishly.
然而 那并不是她的错
Now, it wasn't her fault,
所以我不接受她的辞职
so I refused to accept her resignation.
若你们有同样情况 我也会为你们做同样的事
I would have done the same for any of you in the same situation.
如果你们有麻烦 应找我帮忙
If you are in trouble, come to me,
而不是偷我的东西
don't steal from me.
诚实努力 团结互助
Honest endeavour, together.
这才是塞尔福里奇精神
This is the Spirit of Selfridge's.
夫人 克里诺先生来见您
Your ladyship, Mr Colleano to see you.
我还以为你不来了
I'd given up on you.
可惜 我还带了待煮的鹌鹑肉来
Shame. I've got some spatch-cock quail in here.
你带了待煮的鹌鹑肉进来我的客厅?
You've brought spatch-cock quail into my sitting room?!
我想到它能搭配青酱一同享用
Thought I'd serve it up with a salsa verde.
但如果你不想的话
But if you don't want it...
既然你都来了
Well, you're here now.
带克里诺先生去厨房
Show Mr Colleano the kitchen.
呼!
Brooooom!
嘿 爸爸
Hey, Pa!
汽车摆到橱窗里了吗
Is the motor in the window yet?
明天就摆进去
Going in tomorrow.
- 我能去看吗 - 当然可以
- Can I come see it? - You sure can.
- 那再见啦 - 好的
- See ya! - Alright!
汉弗莱在追赶着什么 他设置了几个陷阱
Humphrey was now after something else. He had made several traps -
你喜欢那些花吗
Did you like the flowers?
非常喜欢
I loved them.
那张卡片上字字真心的
I meant every word of the message.
- 你脸红了 - 才没有
- You're blushing. - I am not!
虽然不像那画家亲你时那样红
Not like you did when the painter man kissed you.
那时你的脸真的很红
Then you went really red.
你是个好厨师
You're a good cook.
坐下
Sit down.
给自己斟杯酒吧
Help yourself to a glass of wine.
那克里诺先生 还是该叫你
So Mr Colleano... Or may I call you...?
维克托
Victor.
维克托 跟我聊聊你自己吧
Victor. Tell me all about yourself.
从头道来
Start from the beginning.
这个很适合你
It suits you.
你该多穿鲜艳点
You should wear more colour.
勒卡雷先生
Mr Leclair!
就当是给你今晚辛勤工作的回报吧
I'd like to give it to you for all your hard work tonight.
我不能接受这个
I couldn't accept this!
收下吧 我明天会付钱的
Take it. I'll pay for it tomorrow.
晚安
Goodnight.
谢谢你
Thank you.
晚安
Good night.
噢不 你不能这样
Oh no, you don't!
我们需要说清楚
We need to have this out.
你和他在这屋子里亲吻就够糟糕的了
It's bad enough that you kiss him in this house -
居然还是在碧翠丝面前
but you do it in front of Beatrice!
你是她母亲啊
Her own mother.
而且 你还骗我
And then, you lied to me.
你明明说什么事都没有
You said that everything was gonna be alright.
但却跟一个廉价画家乱搞关系
But you're having an affair, with some two-bit painter!
还要把画像送到我办公室去
You even sent the portrait to my office!
你到底怎么了 露思
What's happened to you, Rose?
爱伦・乐芙今早来找我
Ellen Love paid me a visit this morning.
爱伦 她想要什么
Ellen? What did she want?
你凭什么就只许州官放火 不许百姓点灯啊
Why does it have to be one rule for you and another for the rest of us?
她说的一切都不是真的
Whatever she said, it's not true.
你是说你和乐芙小姐没有过关系了
So you're telling me you're not having a relationship with Miss Love?
一切都结束了
It's over.
那你呢 你和他在一起过吗
And what about you? Have you been with him?
没有
No.
但就算一起过 你要责备我吗
But would you blame me if I had?
我也不过是有样学样
I'd just be following your example.
别这样说
Don't say that.
这些年来 我独守空房
All these years I have sat at home,
而你却在外面纵情声色
while you've gone out and had your fun!
你以为我愿意这样吗
Do you think that I want to be this way?
你以为我这样很开心吗
Do you think that it makes me happy?
你是说我还应该同情你 对吗
Now I'm meant to feel sorry for you, is that right?
好 或许明天我会 但今晚 你就去下地狱吧
Well, maybe I will tomorrow. But tonight...you can go to hell!
再来一杯
Another one.
- 喝酒呢 老朋友? - 对
- Drinking, old boy? - Yeah.
- 不像你啊 - 还输钱了呢
- Not like you. - And losing too.
我输了不少 你要喝点什么?
I've lost a packet. What can I get you?
- 威士忌 - 威士忌
- Whiskey. - Whiskey.
出什么事了?
What happened?
爱伦今天去找我妻子了
Well... Ellen paid my wife a visit today.
噢
Uh-oh!
露思认为我一无是处
Rose thinks I'm no damn good.
她也许是对的
She may be right.
通常 我都是远离这种毒药的
Normally I stay off this poison.
我父亲就很嗜酒
My father had a penchant for it.
真的?
Really?
你母亲口中的少校可像圣人一般
You mother paints the Major as a bit of a saint.
只能说是 妈妈宁愿记住好时光罢了
Let's just say - Ma likes to remember the good times.
- 我们为什么而喝 - 随便什么吧
- What are we drinking to? - Anything you like.
敬我父亲
To my father!
敬少校
The Major.
敬爸爸和他坚持的一切
To Pa and everything that he stood for!
干杯
Cheers.
再赌几局吧 这正是我所需要的
More cards, that's what I need.
不该回家了吗?
Shouldn't you call it a night?
- 塞尔福里奇先生? - 是
- Mr Selfridge? - Yeah.
有人要见你 抱歉 我拦不住她
Someone to see you. I'm sorry, I couldn't stop her.
你来这里做什么
What are you doing here?
我跟你妻子说了 我是来跟你说的
I told your wife, and I'll tell you
我不会这样轻易被抛弃的
I won't be cast off like a piece of nothing.
你吸药吸得神志不清了 快回家吧
You're doped up and you're not thinking straight. Just go home.
公寓没有了你就变了样
The flat's not the same without you.
求你了 哈里 跟我走吧
Please, Harry. Come with me.
最后一次
One last time.
如果我让你误会了 我很抱歉 真的
I'm sorry if I misled you, I really am.
但你要理解 我是有家室的
But you have to understand, I have a family.
你就跟其他那些人一样
You're just the same as all the others!
你这个浪荡潦倒的混蛋
You are a whore mongering, low-life bastard!
该走了 朋友 该走了
Time to go, old thing. Time to go.
求你别这样对我 哈里 我爱你
Please don't do this to me, Harry. I love you.
走吧
Come on!
- 我爱你 - 走吧
- I love you. - Let's go.
谢谢你 好儿子
Thank you, son.
哈里老兄 我送她上了出租
Harry, old chap? I put her in a cab.
待会我再去看看她是否安好
I'll go and check on her later, see she's all right.
回家吧 回去睡吧
Go home. Get some sleep.
我有一个不能告诉你的秘密
'I've got a secret that I can't tell you!'
爱伦?
Ellen?
天啊!
Jesus!
哈里 你来了
Harry. You came.
快点 我扶你起来
Come on, let's get you up.
你爸才不是战争英雄呢
'Your father's no war hero.'
我似乎没办法摆脱他
'I can't seem to find my way out of it.'
爸爸 你不过是个普通商贩
'Dad, you're nothing but a common huckster.'
但你我血肉相连 不论你喜欢与否
'But I'm your blood and you're mine whether you like it or not.'
跟我走吧 走吧
'Come with me... with me...'
虽然不像那画家亲你时那样红
Not like you did when the painter man kissed you.
这些年来 我独守空房
'All these years I have sat at home!'
潦倒的混蛋!
'..low-life bastard!'
纵情声色
'Have your fun!'
你不过是个普通商贩
'You're nothing but a common huckster.'
不过是个普通商贩
'Nothing but a common huckster.'
你是谁 你是谁
'Who are you?' 'Who are you?'
正如你们所听说的一样
As you all must have heard by now,
下集预告
塞尔福里奇遭遇车祸
老大出了严重的车祸
the Chief had a serious automobile accident.
我是总务主管
I am Chief Of Staff.
商场不能群龙无首 我责无旁贷
This ship needs a Captain. I am that man.
你的勒卡雷先生很难接受 对吧
Taking it bad, isn't he, your Mr Leclair?
他不是我的勒卡雷先生
He's not MY Mr Leclair.
妇女参政权论者明天会路经这栋楼
The Suffragettes are walking past the building tomorrow.
一些商家非常担心此事
Some of the stores are very worried about it.
他们不能踏进这里一步 清楚吗
They are not to set foot within these four walls. Is that clear?
我们明天要有大麻烦了
We've got a real problem on our hands tomorrow.
除非我们采取措施 不然商场真会有麻烦
Unless we do something about it, the store could be in real trouble.